<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>M. avium complex on ntmscope</title>
    <link>http://ntmscope.org/tags/m.-avium-complex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in M. avium complex on ntmscope</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://ntmscope.org/tags/m.-avium-complex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations at this year&#39;s ECCMID, Barcelona, Spain</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/news/post16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/news/post16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/authors/margo-diricks/&#34;&gt;Margo Diricks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/authors/nils-wetzstein/&#34;&gt;Nils Wetzstein&lt;/a&gt; are presenting their newest results on non-tuberculous mycobacteria at this year&#39;s ECCMID in Barcelona Spain, 27th-30th April 2024.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
They will present:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Margo Diricks&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;i&gt;Mycobacterium abscessus transmission and micro-evolution of resistance in a German cystic fibrosis centre&lt;/i&gt;, oral presentation, 29/04/2024, 13:30 in Hall D. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt; Nils Wetzstein&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;i&gt;Clinical and genomic features of M. avium complex: a multi-national European study&lt;/i&gt;, poster, 28/04/2024, 12:00 in the poster area.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
You can find the full program &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eccmid.org/scientific-programme&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;br&gt;
We would be happy to see you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_eco</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/eco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/eco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) are recovered from a variety of environmental samples. In other countries, potable water, for example from shower heads, has been a frequent source. Patients with NTM-pulmonary disease have been shown to acquire their bacterial isolates from their household water samples in some cases. However, in Germany, NTM have not been isolated from water samples until now and only been found in soil, dust, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Isolation of NTM from water samples.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Environmental sampling, culture, molecular identification techniques.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Currently running&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eu.jotform.com/222856429317058&#34;&gt;Include sample&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_MAC</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex is the predominant slow-growing mycobacterium in Europe and North America and consists – among others – of the species &lt;em&gt;M. avium, M. intracellulare&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;M. chimaera&lt;/em&gt;. The latter has been involved in a global outbreak of infections in patients that underwent cardiosurgical interventions. Here, contaminated heater-cooler machines could be identified as point infection source. All three species are present in the environment and have been isolated from water sources in patients homes. However, human-to-human transmission has not been established so far. In CF-patients, &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex is the NTM second most frequently isolated in Europe. If there are dominant circulating clones, as has been described in &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt;, remains unclear until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the genomic epidemiology of &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex in multiple centers in Europe.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Clinical and epidemiological data-analysis, whole genome sequencing, genotypic drug susceptibility testing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Currently recruiting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_registry</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: In contrast to tuberculosis, infections due to non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) are not notifiable. However, there is accumulating evidence that their incidence is increasing in countries with low endemicity of tuberculosis. In addition, the pathogenicity of different NTM varies widely.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the epidemiological and clinical features of patients infected or colonised with non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: The ntmscope_registry will establish needed data collecting tools in a monocentric approach, after an initial test phase the registry will become available to additional centers with the aim of becoming the first NTM-registry in Germany. This is to be achieved with the Institute for Medical Informatics (IMI) of the Goethe University Frankfurt.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Registry currently being constructed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osse-register.de/&#34;&gt;www.osse-register.de&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
