<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SGM on ntmscope</title>
    <link>http://ntmscope.org/tags/sgm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SGM on ntmscope</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://ntmscope.org/tags/sgm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_MAC</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex is the predominant slow-growing mycobacterium in Europe and North America and consists – among others – of the species &lt;em&gt;M. avium, M. intracellulare&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;M. chimaera&lt;/em&gt;. The latter has been involved in a global outbreak of infections in patients that underwent cardiosurgical interventions. Here, contaminated heater-cooler machines could be identified as point infection source. All three species are present in the environment and have been isolated from water sources in patients homes. However, human-to-human transmission has not been established so far. In CF-patients, &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex is the NTM second most frequently isolated in Europe. If there are dominant circulating clones, as has been described in &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt;, remains unclear until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the genomic epidemiology of &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex in multiple centers in Europe.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Clinical and epidemiological data-analysis, whole genome sequencing, genotypic drug susceptibility testing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Currently recruiting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/#contact&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_meta</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/meta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Treatment and management of rare NTM remains a considerable challenge as randomized controlled trials or systematic studies are scarce. Most therapeutic recommendations are based on &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; data or clinical experience with more frequent NTM. The optimal therapy for most infections remains unclear.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of clinical data regarding the clinical manifestations and therapeutic outcomes of rare NTM.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Literature review, (individual patient data) meta analysis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Ongoing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/#contact&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
