<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on ntmscope</title>
    <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on ntmscope</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://ntmscope.org/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>cronoclone</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/chrono_clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/chrono_clone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt; is a multi-drug resistant rapid-growing mycobacterium that causes difficult to treat infections. Especially, patients with predisposing lung conditions, such as cystic fibrosis, are the ones most at risk. It has also been involved in nosocomial transmission during surgical procedures. However, the existence of so-called dominant circulating clones that exist globally and are associated with higher mortality and morbidity have lead to the assumption that inter-human transmission (direct or via fomites) takes place in these NTM. It has been stipulated that this NTM undergoes similar evolutional changes as &lt;em&gt;M. tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; complex before becoming a exclusively pathogenic mycobacterium.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: This study will implement state-of-the-art DNA sequencing and phenotyping technologies for operational research on NTM in CF to address the following hypotheses: i) Whole genome sequencing (WGS) of
sequential &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt; isolates from single patients can identify the occurrence of genomic polymorphisms in NTM associated with virulence and drug resistance, and provide comprehensive typing data to identify transmission. ii) Phenotypic drug susceptibility testing (pDST) can be used to validate genotype/phenotype relations for specific NTM strains and provide functional data on clinical drug susceptibility breakpoints. iii) Comprehensive analysis of sequential NTM isolates from single patients by WGS and pDST will improve prediction of clinical impact of NTM-positive cultures in individual patients.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Expected benefit for CF patients&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New insights into patient-to-patient transmission, evolution of virulence and resistance over time and the correlation of genotype, phenotype and clinical outcome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New evidence to design personalized treatment regimens for CF patients with NTM infections and new directions for future NTM research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Clinical and epidemiological data-analysis, whole genome sequencing, genotypic drug susceptibility testing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Data analysis currently ongoing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image Credit&lt;/em&gt;: REM/SEM analysis, &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt; rough phenotype, F.V. Sotomayor, T. Gutsmann and S. Homolka.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOMA_CF</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/moma_cf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/moma_cf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt; is a multi-drug resistant rapid-growing mycobacterium that causes difficult to treat infections. Especially, patients with predisposing lung conditions, such as cystic fibrosis, are the ones most at risk. It has also been involved in nosocomial transmission during surgical procedures. However, the existence of so-called dominant circulating clones that exist globally and are associated with higher mortality and morbidity have lead to the assumption that inter-human transmission (direct or via fomites) takes place in these NTM. It has been stipulated that this NTM undergoes similar evolutional changes as &lt;em&gt;M. tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; complex before becoming a exclusively pathogenic mycobacterium.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the genomic landscape of &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt; in Germany, especially among CF-patients and the search for the dominant circulating clones in a German collective.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Clinical and epidemiological data-analysis, whole genome sequencing, genotypic drug susceptibility testing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Data analysis completed&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/browser/view/PRJEB44160?show=reads&#34;&gt;European Nucleotide Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/moma_cf_microreact&#34;&gt;Microreact project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_eco</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/eco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/eco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) are recovered from a variety of environmental samples. In other countries, potable water, for example from shower heads, has been a frequent source. Patients with NTM-pulmonary disease have been shown to acquire their bacterial isolates from their household water samples in some cases. However, in Germany, NTM have not been isolated from water samples until now and only been found in soil, dust, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Isolation of NTM from water samples.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Environmental sampling, culture, molecular identification techniques.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Currently running&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eu.jotform.com/222856429317058&#34;&gt;Include sample&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_MAC</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex is the predominant slow-growing mycobacterium in Europe and North America and consists – among others – of the species &lt;em&gt;M. avium, M. intracellulare&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;M. chimaera&lt;/em&gt;. The latter has been involved in a global outbreak of infections in patients that underwent cardiosurgical interventions. Here, contaminated heater-cooler machines could be identified as point infection source. All three species are present in the environment and have been isolated from water sources in patients homes. However, human-to-human transmission has not been established so far. In CF-patients, &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex is the NTM second most frequently isolated in Europe. If there are dominant circulating clones, as has been described in &lt;em&gt;M. abscessus&lt;/em&gt;, remains unclear until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the genomic epidemiology of &lt;em&gt;M. avium&lt;/em&gt; complex in multiple centers in Europe.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Clinical and epidemiological data-analysis, whole genome sequencing, genotypic drug susceptibility testing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Currently recruiting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_meta</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/meta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: Treatment and management of rare NTM remains a considerable challenge as randomized controlled trials or systematic studies are scarce. Most therapeutic recommendations are based on &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; data or clinical experience with more frequent NTM. The optimal therapy for most infections remains unclear.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of clinical data regarding the clinical manifestations and therapeutic outcomes of rare NTM.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Literature review, (individual patient data) meta analysis.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Ongoing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_registry</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: In contrast to tuberculosis, infections due to non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM) are not notifiable. However, there is accumulating evidence that their incidence is increasing in countries with low endemicity of tuberculosis. In addition, the pathogenicity of different NTM varies widely.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the epidemiological and clinical features of patients infected or colonised with non-tuberculous mycobacteria (NTM).
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: The ntmscope_registry will establish needed data collecting tools in a monocentric approach, after an initial test phase the registry will become available to additional centers with the aim of becoming the first NTM-registry in Germany. This is to be achieved with the Institute for Medical Informatics (IMI) of the Goethe University Frankfurt.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Registry currently being constructed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.osse-register.de/&#34;&gt;www.osse-register.de&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/contact/&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntmscope_s</title>
      <link>http://ntmscope.org/project/ntmscope-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ntmscope.org/project/ntmscope-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium simiae&lt;/em&gt; is a slow-growing non-tuberculous mycobacterium that can cause non-tuberculous mycobacterium (NTM) pulmonary disease and extrapulmonary infections. Until now, detailed genomic and clinical characteristics, as well as possible transmission routes of this rare pathogen remain largely unknown. &lt;em&gt;M. simiae&lt;/em&gt; is a member of the &lt;em&gt;M. simiae&lt;/em&gt; complex that comprises &lt;em&gt;M. genavense&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;M. lentiflavum&lt;/em&gt; and others.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigation of the genomic populations of the &lt;em&gt;M. simiae&lt;/em&gt; complex and the investigation of the longitudinal genomic stability within single patients colonised or infected with &lt;em&gt;M. simiae&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Clinical and epidemiological data-analysis, whole genome sequencing, genotypic drug susceptibility testing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Status&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Data analysis completed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/browser/view/PRJEB66336?show=reads&#34;&gt;European Nucleotide Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ntmscope.org/ntmscope_s_microreact&#34;&gt;Microreact project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
